# VIDHU GABA

www.linkedin.com/in/vidhugaba/

vidhu12gaba@gmail.com/+1(437)989-1297

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

Innovative, focused, team player and quick learner who is a tech enthusiast with 2+ years of experience as a UX Designer and Web Developer. I am a professional bringing to the table existing skills in Front-End Developmen $\pi$ t, Software, SEO, UI/UX Development and Data Analysisacross diverse industries. Currently, aspiring to be a UX Designer and Software Developer with a top technology firm.

#### SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

**Certifications: Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2)** | Microsoft Technology Associate **(MTA)**: Programming with Python | SEO Foundations | A2 Diplôme d'Etudes En Langue Française **(DELF)** |

Tools, Technologies, and Frameworks: Figma | Canva | Adobe PhotoShop | HTML5 | CSS | JavaScript | Node.JS (NPM) | Bootstrap | PHP | Java | SQL | R | Python (Numpy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib) | Swift (iOS) | Kotlin (Android) | Git | GitHub | AWS |

Language – Fluent English

Native / Bilingual Hindi

Full Professional French

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Junior Developer (Contract), Douglas Research Centre

May 2022 - July 2022

- Maintaining and updating the server-side database with Front-end improvement
- Improving the system performance and optimizing the website
- Repairing and troubleshooting the system errors and bugs

#### Front-End Developer (Part-time), Saisi Human Capital

Dec 2021 – Aug 2022

- Performing ongoing keyword research including discovery and expansion of keyword opportunities for SEO
- Plan, design, write, modify, integrate, and test web-related code
- Optimizing landing pages for search engine optimization

#### Front-End Developer, Interact Health PRO

Sept 2021 – Dec 2021

- Composed the landing pages for different features involved on the Website and developed the interface on Figma
- Designed and remodeled the mobile application for initial user case testing
- Researching and implementing content recommendations for organic SEO reach

## Data Analyst, Hive.AI, Gurugram

Dec 2020 - Aug 2021

- Conceptualized on projects involved in analyzing data and auditing, while assessing compliance with regulations and controls, using variousschematics, and editing tools to produce a final product and then feed it into the AI Software
- Effectively led a team of 5 staff to analyse data of a large-scale e-commerce company with the help of an AI Software to find discrepancies and resolve them
- Analysed and resolved data discrepancies with the help of AI and troubleshooting teams

## **PROJECTS**

Audio-Video transmitting platform like Zoom with similar features

2020

Research Project on House Price Prediction

- 2019 2020
- Engineer a platform that analyzed the data set of US neighborhoods to calculate the Price of House while considering different attributes affecting the price
- o Used Machine Learning concepts with Python to make a Web based Application

## **EDUCATION**

**Mobile Application Development** 

Sept 2021 - April 2022

Centennial College, Toronto, ON

• GPA 3.8/4.0

Bachelor of Computer Applications Maharaja Surajmal Institute, GGSIPU August 2017 – November 2020

• CGPA 7.38/10

CBSE (Grade / Class 12)

April 2015 – March 2016

The Indian School

• CGPA 8.5/10

# ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

• Certificate of Merit for Independent (B2) Level French at Alliance Française de Delhi

August 2020

• Certificate of Presentation for Research Project at International Web Conference

June 2020

Volunteered to Represent Institut Francaise in India (Campus France Delhi) at France Education Fair

Feb 2020

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

# Web Developer Intern, InfoVue - Adore India, West Bengal

June 2020 - October 2020

- Contributed towards developing Web Applications such as Audio Video transmission and Message Transmission with the organization for the better working of the organization
- Worked on Web Pages manipulation using HTML5, JS, PHP, CSS; Contributed to Content Management System
- Work with the development team to ensure SEO best practices are properly implemented on newly developed code

# UI / UX Designer Intern, Altamkin, Gurugram

August 2020 - September 2020

- Gathered and evaluated user requirements in collaboration with product managers and developer
- Conducted layout adjustments based on user feedback
- Designed graphic user interface elements, like menus, tabs and widgets while adhering to style standards in Figma

#### Trainee, HackVeda Pvt Ltd @MSI, New Delhi

June 2019 - July 2019

- Worked on learning new concept in Python Programming Language and its libraries; implemented the same knowledge on a project
- Manipulation of the acquired data set and implemented Data Science concepts using Python

# Intern, HCL Technologies, Noida

June 2018 - July 2018

- Explored about Telecom Technology application analysis and web development of telephony applications
- Worked on manipulation and graphical representation of the given data set
- Understanding the role of C++ in create applications and its benefits